

# Edmonton, Canada

□ (587) 879-4626 | ■ tkuipers123@gmail.com | ★ tkuipers.ca | 🖸 tkuipers | 🛅 tyler-kuipers | 🞓 Tyler Kuipers

#### **About Me**

I am a senior level Software Developer with hands-on experience in many facets of software development including the SDLC, Agile methodologies, DevOps practices, and mentoring new developers. I am an enthusiastic, supportive team player dedicated to efficiently solving problems. I have proven experience leading teams, helping mentor junior developers, and performing well both individually and in group settings.

### Work Experience\_

Alberta Motor Association Edmonton, Alberta

Insurance Software Architect
I am working as a Software Architect on AMA's insurance systems. Responsibilities include the following:

- Architecting and developing the cloud architecture for AMA's pay-as-you-go insurance policy, accounting for > 1400 new policies sold in the first 4 months. (AWS, Terraform, Java)
- Architecting and helping to implement large updates to our online payment system, helping to enable an omnichannel experience with our insurance policies.
- Architecting and implementing a devops tool to allow our team to
  - create new testing environments in a single command, resulting in a > 90% reduction in time to create new environments. (AWS, Terraform, Python, Jenkins, Docker, Git)
  - create testing databases in a single command, resulting in drastically reduced time to diagnose production issues. (AWS, Terraform, Python)
- Architecting and developing our insurance platform's RESTful APIs to enable our online auto sales platform. (OpenAPI, Gosu, Typescript, Playwright)
- Code reviewing and testing various patches submitted by other developers. (Git, GitHub)
- Improving, enforcing, and gathering feedback on coding standards across the insurance development team, resulting in increased code maintainability and reliability.
- Helping new developers learn how to approach legacy code throughout the insurance platform.

 Vinted
 Berlin, Germany

 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER
 Sept 2022 - Dec 2022

I worked as a Software Developer at Vinted on their shipping platform.

- Working on high level design and implementation of a new shipping platform. (Ruby on Rails, Shopify)
- Writing automated tests for the new shipping platform.

### Arterys Inc. (Aquired by Tempus Labs)

Calgary, Alberta (Remote)

Aug 2021 - Aug 2022

Jan 2023 - Present

I worked as a Software Developer for Arterys on their core platform. Responsibilities include the following:

- Working to integrate various medical detection AI models onto our platform. (Typescript, NodeJS)
- Various bug fixes and feature enhancements throughout the product. (Typescript, NodeJS)
- Working to lower turn-around-time on results of our Al algorithms. (AWS, Chef, Redis)
- Code reviewing and testing various patches submitted by other developers. (Git, GitHub)
- Helping new developers learn how to develop our product suite.
- · Monitor logs and other health checking platforms for problems before clients are impacted. (Elastic, FullStory, Kibana)

#### Alberta Motor Association

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Edmonton, Alberto

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | SOFTWARE TEAM LEAD

Jun 2018 - Feb 2021 | Feb 2021 - Aug 2021

I worked as a Software Developer for AMA's Insurance Division, doing development on its core insurance product. Responsibilities included the following:

- Leading a team of developers working on the AMA's PolicyCenter implementation. (Gosu)
- Leading another team contributing to an organization-wide standards initiative.
- Performing scrum master responsibilities to increase team efficiency. (VSTS, Agile)
- Suggesting and facilitating improvement ideas brought forward by the insurance development team.

I also brought success to our department in the following ways:

- Led an initiative designing and programming the test framework. It has led to a sharp reduction in bugs throughout following projects.
- Planned and implemented the solutions used for online payment on AMA's website, utilizing third-party APIs and Guidewire. (Gosu, JS, OAuth)
- Supported my team through knowledge transfer, guidance, and open dialogue.
- Participated in upgrade assessment with Guidewire to determine the scope and amount of work required to upgrade AMA's instance of Guidewire to the cloud.

 Pleasant Solutions
 Edmonton, Alberta

 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER
 Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

I worked as a full-stack developer on projects highly customized to the client's needs.

• Created the HMI for a concrete distribution plant (C#, TDD).

• Gained experience in leadership roles for small projects.

**Lockheed Martin Canada** 

SOFTWARE ENGINEER ASSOCIATE

Worked as an associate software engineer developing software to be used in CMS 330.

· Contributed to an internal research project, implementing a Data Fusion module for use with Combat Management Systems. (Java, XML, SQL, Oracle ESB)

- · Worked to develop software modules responsible for the management and status of various underwater sensors. (Java, Swing)
- Worked in an Agile SCRUM environment.

The King's University Edmonton, Alberta

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/RESEARCH ASSISTANT

May 2014 - Sep 2016

Halifax, Nova Scotia Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

Worked as a full stack developer; designed and implemented an approach to dynamically reference items both spatially and temporally.

- Designed and built a website that researchers could input information into; viewers could see the data and explore it. (PHP, HTML, VanillaJS, PostgreSQL, PostGIS)
- · Researched the method utilized and authored an undergraduate thesis documenting my contribution to the Edmonton River Atlas Website. (ETFX)

# **Education**

**The Open University** 

MSc. Computing (Software Engineering)

Currently pursuing Master's in Computing at The Open University. **The King's University** 

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Milton Keynes, England (Remote)

May 2024 - Ongoing

Edmonton, Alberta

Sep 2012 - Dec 2016